Damon Chouinard

Software Developer

EXPERIENCE

Event Coordinator/Organizer | Basin Food & Buyer's Expo

JUNE 2019 - NOV 2022, NELSON, BC

- Accountable for all aspects of building this industry event from the ground up.
- Demonstrated ability to address complex issues and find creative solutions within limited timeframes and budgets.
- Executed specific responsibilities within a collaborative environment.
- Assessed feedback and produced reflections in annual final reports that supported the development and direction of future events.

Lead Program Coordinator | Kootenay Food

MAR 2021 - MAR 2022 WINLAW, BC

- Aquired funds through grants to support a local community kitchen project which addressed local food insecurity and resiliency.
- Implemented program directives with partners and staff.
- Surveyed vulnerable populations and examined new approaches to further meet their needs through the program.
- Summarized project outcomes and reflections in final reports.

Independent Contractor | Community Development

JAN 2013 - DEC 2022, NELSON, BC

Executed numerous community and regional projects through contracts or personal initiative and sponsorship. Some highlights are:

- 2018 Kootenay Cannabis Symposium Conceived and organized event that brought together 120 industry stakeholders, from Health Canada to legacy growers etc.
- Live Love Winlaw Community Engagement developed a community survey process that surveyed up to 500 residents with the goal of creating data points to support community development initiatives.

PROJECTS

Designer, Developer | TITLE - MELDER

FEB 2023 - BRAINSTATION - PERSONAL CAPSTONE PROJECT

 Designed and implemented a project that involved front and back end development with the integration of OpenAl's api. The survey-like application takes in open-ended responses and then generates a summary of the inputs and suggestions. fengchoui@gmail.com
250-551-0413
linkedin.com/in/damon-chouinard

https://github.com/MrPreachez

EDUCATION

BrainStation - Alumni Graduate, Software Engineering

NOV 2022 - FEB 2023, TORONTO, ON

Verge Permaculture -Permaculture Design Certificate

FEB 2020 - APRIL 2020, VIRTUALLY, BC

SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node, React, Express, MySQL, Agile Development, Document Object Model (DOM) APIs, RESTful APIs, User Authentication, OAuth, Heroku, GitHub, Jest, Project Planning, Strategic Planning, Report/Analysis Writing, MS Word, Google Docs, Slack.

PROFILE

If there's one thing I've learnt, it is that I love working on a challenge or solution to a problem. Through my experiences in entrepreneurship, community development work and food security projects I have learnt the value of persistence and patience. I believe modern technology can improve our lives in ways we have not yet seen and I look forward to carrying my creative insight and diversity of experience into new directions as a software developer.